Guide to the New York State Nutrition Council records,1939-2007.
New York State Nutrition Council records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State Nutrition Council records, 1939-2007.
2679
New York State Nutrition Council.
1.5 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes of meetings, membership lists, procedures of the council, Historians' reports, Executive Council Board minutes, and related records of the New York State Nutrition Council.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes of meetings, membership lists, procedures of the council, Historians' reports, Executive Council Board minutes, and related records of the New York State Nutrition Council.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State Nutrition Council.
Subjects:
Nutrition--Societies, etc.
Form and Genre Terms:
Minutes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Contents
  - Special Programs Final reports of projects funded by NYSNC, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Special Programs, 1942-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nutrition Institute I, 1939-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Nutrition Institute II, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 50th Anniversary Booklet 4 copies (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Incorporation Documents. Documents pertaining to tax-exempt status, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership Brochures, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1988,1997-2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Resolutions, 1949-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Procedures; Job descriptions of members of the Board of Directors;also contains Constitution, 1965-2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budgets; Financial statements and Treasurer's reports, 1968-2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Nutrition Council Minutes I, 1976-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nutrition Council Minutes II, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nutrition Council Minutes III, 1997-August 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of Executive Committee, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Agency Representation, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Reports; From President to NYSNC public; fundraising materials, 1951-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Membership Lists, 1992-2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Members and Officers, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Membership Lists; Many years missing, 1967-1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Membership Ballots; Contain 1999 revisions to Constitution (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Membership Reports and Notices, 1977-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Board of Directors; lists of Board member names; Many years missing, 1972-2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Governing Policies; Constitution and by-laws, 1952-1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Mid-winter Meetings, 1946-1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Councilor(NYSNC Newsletter)I;missing Fall & Spring '06 & Winter '05, Winter 2001- Fall 2007 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Councilor II; missing Winter'99, Spring & Summer '98, Spring '95, 1992-2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Councilor III; (Vol. 1,Issue 1); missing many issues, 1960-1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Legislation, 1989-1992,2005 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Planning Documents;mission statements;program proposals, 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Local Nutrition Councils, 1967-1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Local Nutrition Grants; Special Projects fund, 1992,1996 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Historians Reports, 1941-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Special Committees; sub-committees on school lunches,the elderly etc, 1948-1966 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Employer Identification Numbers, 1976,1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Annual Conferences 2003-2007, Conference materials, 2003-2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Conference I, "How to Turn Kids onto Healthy Eating", 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Conference II, "Food Play Contract and Follow-up Resources", 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conference "Adolescent Nutrition Issues", 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual Conferences 1994-2000, Conference materials, 1994-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Conference I, "Nutritional Focus on Food Safety", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Conference II, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Nutrition Institute, "Empowering Communities for Health Promotion", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Nutrition Institute,Contains brochures from other years as well, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Biennial Nutrition Institute,"Nutritional Challenges in Health Promotion", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Nutrition Institute,Conference materials, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Nutrition Institute,"Nutrition, Food Choices and Publicity", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - NYSNC WWII Activities, Contains brochures for the public, Correspondence reports on "Adequate Nutrition for the Industrial Workers" (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Civil Defense I, "Emergency feeding in case of enemy attack, How to stock fall-out shelter", 1950s-1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Civil Defense II, 1950s-1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - NYSNC Miscellanous materials; membership lists, minutes etc, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - By-laws and Constitution, 1987-2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with local nutrition councils from the 1980s; Co-operative Extension agents (Box 4, Folder 3)